

# Profile

I have been working with web development for the past 7 years, participating in a wide range of projects in his portfolio - from building an e-commerce platform, to creating a web presence for local small businesses, to scaling a small start-up to a corporate level company.

I consider myself a self-motivated developer with a solid base of knowledge that allows me to learn fast - I love experimenting and learning technologies that can ease the development process and that can have a great impact in people's lives and/or take projects to the next level.

My toolbox includes Golang, PHP, ReactJS, Vue.js, SQL, TDD, System Designs, Kubernetes, Docker and more. I consider myself as a full-stack with backend and DevOps focus but I can also actively contribute to front-end tasks.

Currently an enthusiast in Rust, blockchain and smart-contracts development.

# Employment History

Senior Full-stack Developer @ smava

Berlin, Germany | October 2021 — Present

Took part in major projects in the Offerings, Customer Area and Checkout domains with the integration of Video Identity and Digital Signature processes. Performed diverse DevOps tasks such as the migration of Elastic Beanstalk services to Kubernetes (EKS) leading to a drastic reduction of infrastructure costs and introduction of advanced Spinnaker pipelines which allowed the lead to a leaner development experience.

Implemented new microservices in Golang such as a Scanned Documents handling service that drastically reduced operational costs by automating the reception and integration of contracts received by Postal into the company's CRM tool.

### Senior Full-stack Developer (Team lead) @ Studydrive

Berlin, Germany | January 2017 — October 2021

As one of the first developers of the start-up, managed to introduce a new technology stack and a reusable component system for the front-end of the platform which led to a more sustainable and easy way of approaching front-end projects . Strategized and kick-started the process of breaking the monolithic application into scalable and highly available micro services.

Took part in highly complex systems - such as:

- An Advertisement and User Group targeting system
- A gamification system for students that included a payment system
- Implemented job board integrated with third-party systems (ETL)
- Optimization of the posts feed algorithm
- A front-end relaunch of the platform switching the front-end from reactive to a responsive

#### **Address**

Okerstraße 35, 12049 Berlin, Germany

### Contact

+49 0162 9297734

thiago.megermello@gmail.com

### **Nationality**

Portuguese and Brazilian

#### Links

LinkedIn

Github

@thizaom

#### **Skills**

Golang

PHP (Laravel)

Vue.js

ReactIS

Amazon Web Services

Docker

Kubernetes

Terraform

C

# Others:

Shell Script, Sass, Tailwind.CSS, Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Jest, Git, JIRA, Redis, ElasticSearch, Solidity, Substrate

#### Languages

Portuguese

English

German

Czech

#### **Hobbies**

Collecting vinyls, attending
Post-hardcore/Metalcore/Punk Rock
concerts, nature photography and
third-wave coffee - has been trying to
find the perfect coffee beans for each of
his projects;)

# Associate-Lead Developer @ Vizad Solutions

Curitiba, Brazil | March 2015 — December 2016

Managed an e-commerce platform and launched and led a digital marketing company focused on commercialization of Google Products (Street View and AdWords) and retails website development in Laravel and Wordpress.

# Technical Consultant @ Bohemiasoft S.r.o.

České Budějovice, Czech Republic | September 2013 — March 2015

Development of a Brazilian e-Commerce platform, adapting the system for the accounting reality of the market. Implementation of a Mobile Application prototype and development for Android (Java) and Windows Phone (C#) for the e-Commerce customers.

# Advisory Consultant @ Ernst & Young (EY)

Curitiba, Brazil | October 2011 — March 2013

Performed external audit (contracts, accounting and processes) in customers mainly on the Electric Energy segment. Made use of ACL for data analysis and issues identification in customers systems and developed VBA tools for teams to improve team performance and ensure high quality deliveries. Recognized as the best trainee of the region which led to a promotion.

### SAS Developer and Services Analyst @ HSBC Bank

Curitiba, Brazil | June 2009 — October 2011

Developed ETL systems in SAS Base 9.0, documented, modeled Data Cubes and Data marts that fed IBM Cognos to generate reports for many of the bank departments. Execution of periodic management reports and automation/redesign of internal processes.

As a third-party consultant developed an internal portal for all relationship managers and operational managers of HSBC Brazil to access their pending contracts.

### Education

# Post-graduation, Internet of Things and Embedded Systems

O Universidade Positivo

Curitiba, Brazil and Berlin, Germany | June 2016 — December 2018

## **Bachelor, Information Systems**

@ Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná

Curitiba, Brazil | January 2007 — December 2011

# Courses

# The Complete Elixir and Phoenix Bootcamp

Udemy

### Web Development with Elixir

Udemy

# **Development of Modern Applications and Scalable Microservices**

School of Net | January 2020 — March 2020

### **Certified AWS Cloud Developer 2019**

A Cloud Guru | August 2019 — September 2020

### **Laravel From Scratch and many others**

Laracasts

#### Latest books read...

- Programming Rust Fast, Safe
   Systems Development
   Jim Blandy, Jason Orendorff & Leonora
   F.S.Tindal
- Go in ActionWilliam Kennedy
- Domain-driven Design (DDD) -Tackling complexity in the heart of software
   Eric Evans
- Refactoring Improving the Design of Existing Code
   Martin Fowler
- Providence<u>Max Barry</u>
- The Pragmatic Programmer
   <u>David Thomas. Andrew Hunt</u>
- South of the border, west of the Sun <u>Murakami</u>